Sudeep Basnet

sudbasnet.github.io | linkedin.com/in/sudeepbasnet

Address: 5277 W 82nd ST

Bloomington, MN

Phone: **402-617-1329**

Email: **sudbasnet10@gmail.com**

SUMMARY

Dedicated, career-oriented individual with professional experience in Software & Database Engineering, and 2.5 years of Scientific Research. Graduated with a master's degree in Computer Science. Has worked in Agile methodology and used technology such as Python, C#, R and JavaScript on Windows and Linux platforms.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C#, R, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, SQL

Other Technical: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Database Development, Systems Administration (LINUX),

Snowflake Cloud DW, Oracle, GIT and SVN, JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Technical Consultant - Retail Analytics & Supply Chain Technologies | Oct 2019 - Current

Logic Information Systems, Bloomington, MN

- Developing omni-channel e-commerce solutions with C# in .NET and .NET Core.
- Designed Cloud Data Warehouse and ETL pipelines in *Snowflake* along with stored procedures in *JavaScript*, automated data loading with *Python*, and managed *computing clusters*.
- Debugged and resolved issues in reporting dashboards of using MicroStrategy Developer, MicroStrategy Architect and MicroStrategy Intelligence Server.

Graduate Research Assistant | Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)</u>

- *Scientific Data Analysis* and Data Management using *Python* and *R* with packages like *scipy*, *scikit-learn*, *pandas* and *numpy*, utilized parallel computing on Nebraska's second-fastest High-Performance Computing servers.
- Developed a scalable clustering algorithm in *Python* to perform unsupervised learning on GIS data, with performance gain up to 60% compared to state-of-art algorithms. Published and presented Research Paper.
- Development and management of *PHP* backed application, and Data Visualization using *HTML/CSS*, *KnockoutJS*, *Google Maps JavaScript API* and *MySQL* database. (<u>View</u>)
- Developed Agent-based simulation model in *Java* to simulate and predict social unrest on a geographic and temporal scale. (Github Link)

Software Engineer - Data Operations | July 2012 - Dec 2016

Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Nepal | (Subsidiary of COTIVITI HEALTHCARE, Waltham MA)

- Experienced in Software Development using Oracle 11g and Java on Windows and UNIX platforms, involved in Import, Analysis, Designing & Development, Testing and Production support phases.
- Data Analysis of US healthcare data (HIPAA protected medical data). Prepared Analytical Reports per client-requirements using OBIEE and BIP.
- Implemented Oracle PL/SQL procedures, functions, triggers and packages for data management and statistical report generation on US healthcare data.
- Developed ETL procedures, documented and validated complex business rules for data transformation. Prepared technical specification, reviewed code, and performed unit testing for client-specific change requests.
- Optimized multiple large clients by 60 70% in processing time using parallel processes, re-designing back-end jobs, performance tuning, normalization and query optimization.
- Led multiple teams of Software Engineers through different projects for 2 years. Responsible for Code Quality, Code Reviews, Design Reviews, Code documentation and Design documentation for maintainability.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.8) | Jan 2017 - August 2019

University of Nebraska - Lincoln, NE, USA

Relevant Courses: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Systems Administration, GIS